Guide to the Fernando Alegria Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 13. Audiovisual materials
  - Talk on Asturias [sound recording], 1975 Mar. Roundtable: Nicolas Guzman, Braulio Arena, Fernando Alegria, 1975 Mar., 1 sound tape reel (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Tengo Puerto Rico en mi corazon [sound recording] / Pepe y Flora, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - El toro [sound recording] / Pepe y Flora, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Arnold Toynbee, 1955 Apr. [sound recording]. McCarthy, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Atahualpa Yupanqui, no. 3 [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Beyond the rainbow [sound recording] / Joakin Bello. -- New York: GAIA Records, 1988, 1 sound disc: digital (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Viva Chile M....! [sound recording] / de Fernando Alegria; interpretacion de Alex Tinne; Cuecas / de Fernando Alegria y Angel Parra; interpretacion de Angel Parra. -- Hollywood, Calif.: Ediciones de la Frontera, 1973, 1 sound disc; 7 in. (cy 1) (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Viva Chile M....! [sound recording] / de Fernando Alegria; interpretacion de Alex Tinne; Cuecas / de Fernando Alegria y Angel Parra; interpretacion de Angel Parra. -- Hollywood, Calif.: Ediciones de la Frontera, 1973, 1 sound disc; 7 in. (cy 2) (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Viva Chile M....! [sound recording] / de Fernando Alegria; interpretacion de Alex Tinne; Cuecas / de Fernando Alegria y Angel Parra; interpretacion de Angel Parra. -- Hollywood, Calif.: Ediciones de la Frontera, 1973, 1 sound disc; 7 in. (cy 3) (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Viva Chile M....! [sound recording] / de Fernando Alegria; interpretacion de Alex Tinne; Cuecas / de Fernando Alegria y Angel Parra; interpretacion de Angel Parra. -- Hollywood, Calif.: Ediciones de la Frontera, 1973, 1 sound disc; 7 in. (cy 4) (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Viva Chile M....! [sound recording] / de Fernando Alegria; interpretacion de Alex Tinne; Cuecas / de Fernando Alegria y Angel Parra; interpretacion de Angel Parra. -- Hollywood, Calif.: Ediciones de la Frontera, 1973, 1 sound disc; 7 in. (cy 5) (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Canción para Pablo [sound recording] / presenta a Rolando Alarcón y Los Emigrantes. -- [Santiago]: El Departamento de Cultura y Publicaciones del Ministerio de Educación, 1972, 1 sound disc; 7 in. (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Pablo Neruda (1904-1973) [sound recording]. -- Hungary: Hungaraton, n.d., 1 sound disc; 7 in. (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Habla y canta [sound recording] / Victor Jara. -- Cuba: Casa de Las Americas, 1978, 1 sound disc; 7 in. (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Giusepe el zapatero [sound recording] / Guillermo de Ciancio; [performed by] Garlos Gardel. Quien tuviera 18 años / Guillermo D. Barbieri; [performed by] Carlos Gardel. -- Buenos Aires: Industrias Electricas y Musicales Odeon, n.d., 1 sound disc; 10 in. (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Canción de Cuna [sound recording] / Jose A. Diez Gomez, Jose M. Rizzuti; [performed by] Garlos Gardel. Ramona / Enrique Cadicamo, Mabel Wayne; [performed by] Carlos Gardel. -- Buenos Aires: Industrias Electricas y Musicales Odeon, n.d., 1 sound disc; 10 in. (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Libro del Mar / Sabat Ercasty. Nuevo Mundo / Luis Franco, n.d., 1 microfilm reel (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - El mundo folklorico de Rolando Alarcón [sound recording], n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Entre ponerle y no ponerle [sound recording]; Población Callampa; Viva Chile mierda, n.d., 1 sound tape reel (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Gabriela Mistral [sound recording]: discurso, n.d., 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7-1/2 ips (Box 90, Folder 4)
- Series 14. Personal Papers
  - U.S. Naturalization papers (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - U.S. diplomatic identification card (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Instituto Literario y Cultural Hispanico. Honorary diploma (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Fernando Alegria's birth certificate, 1919 Nov. 6 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Medical examination / nutrient summary results for Fernando Alegria, 1991 July (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Chile. Carnet de enrolamiento (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Chile. Cedula nacional de identidad (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Universidad de Chile. Cedula de identidad universitaria (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Chilean passports, 6 items (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Chile. Exile papers (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Department of State. Exemption card (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Department of State. Passports, 2 items (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - California voter registration card (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - Republica de El Salvador. Tourist visa (Box 91, Folder 14)
  - Instituto Cultural Ruben Dario. Diploma de honor, 1988 July 30 (Box 91, Folder 15)
  - City of Merida, Venezuela. Certificate of hospitality, 1967 Aug. 3 (Box 91, Folder 16)
  - Alegria Toro, Santiago. Cedual de identidad personal (Box 91, Folder 17)
  - Handmade card / Raul Fernando Alegria 1923 (Box 91, Folder 18)
  - A man: ams / Isabel Alegria, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 19)
  - Address book (Box 91, Folder 20)
  - Address book (Box 91, Folder 21)
  - Homenaje = A tribute: los 80 años de Fernando Alegria. -- Berkeley, Calif.: Centro Cultural La Peña, 1998, 1 v. (Box 91, Folder 22)
  - Purchase and sale of land parcel in Chile (Box 91, Folder 23)
  - Astrological chart (Box 91, Folder 24)
  - Playbills (Box 91, Folder 25)
  - Alegria, Daniel. Journal for Francis (Box 91, Folder 26)
  - Alegria, Daniel S. Selective service classification, 1970 (Box 91, Folder 27)
  - Melendez, Carmen Letona (wife). Obituary, 1994 (Box 91, Folder 28)
  - Escuelas Publicas de Chile. Certificado anual, 1924 (Box 91, Folder 29)
  - Compañia Sud-America de Vapores. Ticket, 1937 (Box 91, Folder 30)
  - University of California. Program of the final exam for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy of Raul Fernando Alegria, 1947 May 2 (Box 91, Folder 31)
  - Plaque [presented] to Fernando Alegria / A.A.T.S.P., Northwest Pennsylvania Chapter, 1981 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Plaque: Medalla de oro y placa en homenaje a Fernando Alegria / A.A.T.S.P., Northwest Pennsylvania Chapter, 1983 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Plaque: Stanford University. Dept. of Spanish and Portuguese, Sadie Dernham Patek Professorship, 1988 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Diplomas, 1982; 1987; 1998 (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Alegria family album, ca. 1924-1973 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Diplomas, awards, etc. (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - La Real Academia Española certificate, 1989 (Box Ne1, Folder 1)
- Series 15. Biographical information
  - Article on Fernando Alegria: 1st proof set. -- OAS Americas Magazine (Spanish), 1992 Nov. 6 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Fernando Alegria curriculum vita (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Fernando Alegria curriculum vita (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Fernando Alegria curriculum vita (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Biography (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Fernando Alegria. -- In Bigraphical dictionary of Hispanic literature in the United States. -- New York: Greenwood Press, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - Araya Salfate, Ivan Orlando. The concept of Chilenidad in the prose works of Fernando Alegria. -- M.Litt. Thesis, University of Bristol, 1988 (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - Dyson, John P. Los cuentos de Fernando Alegria: tms, n.d., 30 p. (Box 92, Folder 11)
- Series 16. Recortes / Clippings
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1939 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1940 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1943 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1955 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1958 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1960 (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1961 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1962 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1963 (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1964 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1969 (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1970 (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1971 (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1972 (Box 93, Folder 19)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1973 (Box 93, Folder 20)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1974 (Box 93, Folder 21)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1975 (Box 93, Folder 22)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1976 (Box 93, Folder 23)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1977 (Box 93, Folder 24)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1978 (Box 93, Folder 25)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1979 (Box 93, Folder 26)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1980 (Box 93, Folder 27)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1983 (Box 93, Folder 28)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1984 (Box 93, Folder 29)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1985 (Box 93, Folder 30)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1987 (Box 93, Folder 31)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1988 (Box 93, Folder 32)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1989 (Box 93, Folder 33)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1992 (Box 93, Folder 34)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1993 (Box 93, Folder 35)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1994 (Box 93, Folder 36)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1995 (Box 93, Folder 37)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1996 (Box 93, Folder 38)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, 1997 (Box 93, Folder 39)
  - Recortes = Clippings re: Alegria, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 40)
  - Recortes = clippings: of articles by Alegria n.d. (Box 93, Folder 41)
  - Reviews: Allende: a novel n.d. (Box 93, Folder 42)
  - Reviews: Amerika, Amerikka, Amerikkka n.d. (Box 93, Folder 43)
  - Reviews: Breve historia de la novela hispanoamericana n.d. (Box 93, Folder 44)
  - Reviews: Caballo de copas n.d. (Box 93, Folder 45)
  - Reviews: Especie de memorias n.d. (Box 93, Folder 46)
  - Reviews: La poesia chilena del Siglo XIX n.d. (Box 93, Folder 47)
  - Reviews: Las noches del cazador n.d. (Box 93, Folder 48)
  - Reviews: Literatura chilena del Siglo XX n.d. (Box 93, Folder 49)
  - Reviews: Los dias contados n.d. (Box 93, Folder 50)
  - Reviews: Mañana los guerreros n.d. (Box 93, Folder 51)
  - Reviews: Maratón del Palomo n.d. (Box 93, Folder 52)
  - Reviews: My horse Gonzales n.d. (Box 93, Folder 53)
  - Reviews: Rebelión de los placeres n.d. (Box 93, Folder 54)
  - Reviews: Viva Chile M....! n.d. (Box 93, Folder 55)
  - Reviews: Walt Whitman en Hispanoamerica n.d. (Box 93, Folder 56)
  - Biblioteca Ayacucho 1975 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Coloquio sobre la Novela Hispanoamericana, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Coloquio, UCLA, 1976 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Congreso de la Narrativa Latinoamericana, 1974 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Congreso de Literatura Iberoamericana, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Congreso Internacional de Literatura, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Encuentro de Escritores Latinoamericanos, 1975 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Escuela de Verano, 1958 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Escuela Internacional de Verano, 1962 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Festival del Sexto Sol, 1974 (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Fiesta Chilena de Patenquicha, 1972 (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Portland Poetry Festival, 1974 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Primer Taller de Escritores [1 of 2] 1960 (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - Primer Taller de Escritores [2 of 2] 1960 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Talleres Literarios, Universidad de Concepción 1960 (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Empresa Zig-Zag n.d. (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - La Epoca n.d. (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - Premio Internacional de Novela Romulo Gallegos, 1993 (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - Teatro Experimental, Chile n.d. (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - Allende, Salvador n.d. (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - Allende G., Laura n.d. (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - Campos, Javier n.d. (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - Cortazar, Julio n.d. (Box 94, Folder 23)
  - Ginsberg, Allen n.d. (Box 94, Folder 24)
  - Guerra, Lucia n.d. (Box 94, Folder 25)
  - Guzman Cruchaga, Juan n.d. (Box 94, Folder 26)
  - Huidobro, Vicente n.d. (Box 94, Folder 27)
  - Neruda, Pablo n.d. (Box 94, Folder 28)
  - Orrego, Carmen n.d. (Box 94, Folder 29)
  - Roa Bastos, Augusto n.d. (Box 94, Folder 30)
  - Trujillo, Roberto n.d. (Box 94, Folder 31)
  - Valle, Juvencio n.d. (Box 94, Folder 32)
  - Zurita, Raul n.d. (Box 94, Folder 33)
  - Chile n.d. (Box 94, Folder 34)
  - Chile. Golpe de estado = Coup d'etat n.d. (Box 94, Folder 35)
  - Los desaparacidos = The disappeared n.d. (Box 94, Folder 36)
  - Partido Comunista de Chile = Communist Party of Chile n.d. (Box 94, Folder 37)
  - Reagan Administration n.d. (Box 94, Folder 38)
  - Scrapbook (Box 95, Folder 1)
    Contains clippings of articles re: prominent Latin American authors.
  - Primer Encuento de Escritores Americanos: scrapbook 1960, 1 v. (Box 96, Folder 1)
    Contains clippings of articles re: the first Latina American writers conference in January 1960.
  - Caballo de copas = My horse Gonzales: scrapbook, 1958, 1 v.; missing front board (Box 96, Folder 2)
    Contains clippings of articles and reviews of Alegria's Caballo de Copas, Engl. trans. My horse Gonzales.
  - Untitled scrapbook, 1960 - 1961, 1 v. (Box 96, Folder 3)
    Contains clippings of articles re: various writers conferences.
  - Lautaro: scrapbook, 1948, 1 v.; front board loose. (Box 97, Folder 1)
    Contains clippings of articles re: Alegria's Lautaro.
  - Untitled scrapbook, n.d., 1 v. with various tls tipped in. (Box 97, Folder 2)
    Contains clippings of articles and reviews of Alegria's writing.
  - Election of Salvador Allende as President of Chile: various newspapers, 1970 (Box 98)
- Series 17. Posters
  - Posters: slides, 96 items (Box 102, Folder 1)
    Includes multipe copies of slides taken of the posters in this series.
  - Posters: slides, 73 items (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Posters (Box 101, Folder 6)
    Includes posters for readings by Alegria; conferences; performances by Inti-Illimani and other Chilean groups; etc.
  - Posters, 8 items (Box Ne1, Folder 1)
    Includes posters for readings by Alegria; conferences; performances by various Chilean groups; etc.
  - Posters, 7 items (Box Ne1, Folder 2)
    Includes posters for writers conferences; performances by various Chilean groups; political rallies, political movements, political parties, etc.
  - Posters, 7 items (Box Ne1, Folder 3)
  - Posters, 9 items (Box Ne1, Folder 4)
  - Posters, 9 items (Box Ne1, Folder 5)
- Series 18. Artwork
  - Fernando Alegria: portrait / Velasco, 1977, oil on canvas (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Arenas, Braulio. Mujer en un sillon con un ramo de flores, collage (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous artwork (Box 101, Folder 9)
- Series 19. Books